<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmldoc>
  <copyright>SAME AS NELSON SOFTWARE</copyright>

  <language>en_US</language>
  <keyword>slicot_mb03rd</keyword>
  <short_description>Reduction of a real Schur form matrix to a block-diagonal form.</short_description>

  <syntax>
    <syntax_item>[A_OUT, X_OUT, NBLCKS, BLSIZE, WR, WI, INFO] = slicot_mb03rd(JOBX, SORT, PMAX, A_IN, X_IN, TOL)</syntax_item>
  </syntax>
  
  <param_input>
  
    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>JOBX</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies whether or not the transformations are accumulated, as follows: = 'N':  The transformations are not accumulated; = 'U':  The transformations are accumulated in X (the given matrix X is updated)</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>SORT</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies whether or not the diagonal blocks of the real Schur form are reordered, as follows: = 'N':  The diagonal blocks are not reordered; = 'S':  The diagonal blocks are reordered before each step of reduction, so that clustered eigenvalues appear in the same block; = 'C':  The diagonal blocks are not reordered, but the "closest-neighbour" strategy is used instead of the standard "closest to the mean" strategy. = 'B':  The diagonal blocks are reordered before each step of reduction, and the "closest-neighbour" strategy is used.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>PMAX</param_name>
      <param_description>An upper bound for the infinity norm of elementary submatrices of the individual transformations used for reduction</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>A_IN</param_name>
      <param_description>the leading N-by-N part of this array must contain the matrix A to be block-diagonalized, in real Schur form.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>X_IN</param_name>
      <param_description>if JOBX = 'U', the leading N-by-N part of this array must contain a given matrix X.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>TOL</param_name>
      <param_description>The tolerance to be used in the ordering of the diagonal blocks of the real Schur form matrix.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

  </param_input>

  <param_output>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>A_OUT</param_name>
      <param_description>the leading N-by-N part of this array contains the computed block-diagonal matrix, in real Schur canonical form. The non-diagonal blocks are set to zero.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>X_OUT</param_name>
      <param_description>if JOBX = 'U', the leading N-by-N part of this array contains the product of the given matrix X and the transformation matrix that reduced A to block-diagonal form. The transformation matrix is itself a product of non-orthogonal similarity transformations having elements with magnitude less than or equal to PMAX. If JOBX = 'N', this array is not referenced</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>NBLCKS</param_name>
      <param_description>The number of diagonal blocks of the matrix A.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>BLSIZE</param_name>
      <param_description>The first NBLCKS elements of this array contain the orders of the resulting diagonal blocks of the matrix A.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>WR</param_name>
      <param_description>real parts of the eigenvalues of the matrix A.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>WI</param_name>
      <param_description>imaginary parts of the eigenvalues of the matrix A.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>INFO</param_name>
      <param_description> = 0:  successful exit;</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

  </param_output>



  <description>
  <p>To reduce a matrix A in real Schur form to a block-diagonal form using well-conditioned non-orthogonal similarity transformations. The condition numbers of the transformations used for reduction are roughly bounded by PMAX*PMAX, where PMAX is a given value. The transformations are optionally postmultiplied in a given matrix X. The real Schur form is optionally ordered, so that clustered eigenvalues are grouped in the same block.</p>
  </description>

  <used_function>MB03RD</used_function>
  <bibliography>http://slicot.org/objects/software/shared/doc/MB03RD.html</bibliography>

<examples>
  <example_item>
    <example_item_type>nelson</example_item_type>
    <example_item_description></example_item_description>
    <example_item_data><![CDATA[N = 8;
PMAX = 1.D03;
TOL = 1.D-2;
JOBX = 'U';
SORT = 'S';
A_IN = [1.   -1.    1.    2.    3.    1.    2.    3.;
   1.    1.    3.    4.    2.    3.    4.    2.;
   0.    0.    1.   -1.    1.    5.    4.    1.;
   0.    0.    0.    1.   -1.    3.    1.    2.;
   0.    0.    0.    1.    1.    2.    3.   -1.;
   0.    0.    0.    0.    0.    1.    5.    1.;
   0.    0.    0.    0.    0.    0.    0.99999999   -0.99999999;
   0.    0.    0.    0.    0.    0.    0.99999999    0.99999999];
X_IN = zeros(N, N);
[A_OUT, X_OUT, NBLCKS, BLSIZE, WR, WI, INFO] = slicot_mb03rd(JOBX, SORT, PMAX, A_IN, X_IN, TOL)]]>
    </example_item_data>
  </example_item>

</examples>

  <history>
    <history_item>
      <history_version>1.0.0</history_version>
      <history_description>initial version</history_description>
    </history_item>
  </history>

  <authors>
    <author_item>SLICOT Documentation</author_item>
  </authors>
</xmldoc>


