<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmldoc>
  <copyright>SAME AS NELSON SOFTWARE</copyright>

  <language>en_US</language>
  <keyword>slicot_sg02ad</keyword>
  <short_description>Solution of continuous- or discrete-time algebraic Riccati equations for descriptor systems.</short_description>

  <syntax>
    <syntax_item>[RCONDU, X, ALFAR, ALFAI, BETA, S, T, U, IWARN, INFO] = slicot_sg02ad(DICO, JOBB, FACT, UPLO, JOBL, SCAL, SORT, ACC, P, A, E, B, Q, R, L, TOL)</syntax_item>
  </syntax>
  
  <param_input>
  
    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>DICO</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies the type of Riccati equation to be solved as follows: = 'C':  Equation (1), continuous-time case; = 'D':  Equation (2), discrete-time case.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>JOBB</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies whether or not the matrix G is given, instead of the matrices B and R, as follows: = 'B':  B and R are given; = 'G':  G is given.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>FACT</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies whether or not the matrices Q and/or R (if JOBB = 'B') are factored, as follows: = 'N':  Not factored, Q and R are given; = 'C':  C is given, and Q = C'C; = 'D':  D is given, and R = D'D; = 'B':  Both factors C and D are given, Q = C'C, R = D'D.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>UPLO</param_name>
      <param_description>If JOBB = 'G', or FACT = 'N', specifies which triangle of the matrices G, or Q and R, is stored, as follows: = 'U':  Upper triangle is stored; = 'L':  Lower triangle is stored.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>JOBL</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies whether or not the matrix L is zero, as follows: = 'Z':  L is zero; = 'N':  L is nonzero. JOBL is not used if JOBB = 'G' and JOBL = 'Z' is assumed. SLICOT Library routine SB02MT should be called just before SG02AD, for obtaining the results when JOBB = 'G' and JOBL = 'N'.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>SCAL</param_name>
      <param_description>If JOBB = 'B', specifies whether or not a scaling strategy should be used to scale Q, R, and L, as follows: = 'G':  General scaling should be used; = 'N':  No scaling should be used. SCAL is not used if JOBB = 'G'.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>SORT</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies which eigenvalues should be obtained in the top of the generalized Schur form, as follows: = 'S':  Stable   eigenvalues come first; = 'U':  Unstable eigenvalues come first.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>ACC</param_name>
      <param_description>Specifies whether or not iterative refinement should be used to solve the system of algebraic equations giving the solution matrix X, as follows: = 'R':  Use iterative refinement; = 'N':  Do not use iterative refinement.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>P</param_name>
      <param_description>The number of system outputs. If FACT = 'C' or 'D' or 'B', P is the number of rows of the matrices C and/or D.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>A</param_name>
      <param_description>The leading N-by-N part of this array must contain the state matrix A of the descriptor system.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>E</param_name>
      <param_description>The leading N-by-N part of this array must contain the matrix E of the descriptor system.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>B</param_name>
      <param_description>If JOBB = 'B', the leading N-by-M part of this array must contain the input matrix B of the system.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>Q</param_name>
      <param_description>If FACT = 'N' or 'D', the leading N-by-N upper triangular part (if UPLO = 'U') or lower triangular part (if UPLO = 'L') of this array must contain the upper triangular part or lower triangular part, respectively, of the symmetric state weighting matrix Q. The stricly lower triangular part (if UPLO = 'U') or stricly upper triangular part (if UPLO = 'L') is not referenced. If FACT = 'C' or 'B', the leading P-by-N part of this array must contain the output matrix C of the system. If JOBB = 'B' and SCAL = 'G', then Q is modified internally, but is restored on exit.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>R</param_name>
      <param_description>If FACT = 'N' or 'C', the leading M-by-M upper triangular part (if UPLO = 'U') or lower triangular part (if UPLO = 'L') of this array must contain the upper triangular part or lower triangular part, respectively, of the symmetric input weighting matrix R. The stricly lower triangular part (if UPLO = 'U') or stricly upper triangular part (if UPLO = 'L') is not referenced. If FACT = 'D' or 'B', the leading P-by-M part of this array must contain the direct transmission matrix D of the system. If JOBB = 'B' and SCAL = 'G', then R is modified internally, but is restored on exit.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>L</param_name>
      <param_description>If JOBL = 'N' and JOBB = 'B', the leading N-by-M part of this array must contain the cross weighting matrix L. If JOBB = 'B' and SCAL = 'G', then L is modified internally, but is restored on exit.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

    <param_input_item>
      <param_name>TOL</param_name>
      <param_description>The tolerance to be used to test for near singularity of the original matrix pencil, specifically of the triangular M-by-M factor obtained during the reduction process.</param_description>
    </param_input_item>

  </param_input>

  <param_output>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>RCONDU</param_name>
      <param_description>If N > 0 and INFO = 0 or INFO = 7, an estimate of the reciprocal of the condition number (in the 1-norm) of the N-th order system of algebraic equations from which the solution matrix X is obtained.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>X</param_name>
      <param_description>If INFO = 0, the leading N-by-N part of this array contains the solution matrix X of the problem.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>ALFAR</param_name>
      <param_description>The generalized eigenvalues of the 2N-by-2N matrix pair, ordered as specified by SORT (if INFO = 0, or INFO >= 5).</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>ALFAI</param_name>
      <param_description>The generalized eigenvalues of the 2N-by-2N matrix pair, ordered as specified by SORT (if INFO = 0, or INFO >= 5).</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>BETA</param_name>
      <param_description>The generalized eigenvalues of the 2N-by-2N matrix pair, ordered as specified by SORT (if INFO = 0, or INFO >= 5).</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>S</param_name>
      <param_description>The leading 2N-by-2N part of this array contains the ordered real Schur form S of the first matrix in the reduced matrix pencil associated to the optimal problem, corresponding to the scaled Q, R, and L, if JOBB = 'B' and SCAL = 'G'.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>T</param_name>
      <param_description>The leading 2N-by-2N part of this array contains the ordered upper triangular form T of the second matrix in the reduced matrix pencil associated to the optimal problem, corresponding to the scaled Q, R, and L, if JOBB = 'B' and SCAL = 'G'.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>U</param_name>
      <param_description>The leading 2N-by-2N part of this array contains the right transformation matrix U which reduces the 2N-by-2N matrix pencil to the ordered generalized real Schur form (S,T).</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>IWARN</param_name>
      <param_description> = 0:  no warning; = 1:  the computed solution may be inaccurate due to poor scaling or eigenvalues too close to the boundary of the stability domain (the imaginary axis, if DICO = 'C', or the unit circle, if DICO = 'D').</param_description>
    </param_output_item>

    <param_output_item>
      <param_name>INFO</param_name>
      <param_description> = 0:  successful exit; = 1:  if the computed extended matrix pencil is singular, possibly due to rounding errors; = 2:  if the QZ algorithm failed; = 3:  if reordering of the generalized eigenvalues failed; = 4:  if after reordering, roundoff changed values of some complex eigenvalues so that leading eigenvalues in the generalized Schur form no longer satisfy the stability condition; this could also be caused due to scaling; = 5:  if the computed dimension of the solution does not equal N; = 6:  if the spectrum is too close to the boundary of the stability domain; = 7:  if a singular matrix was encountered during the computation of the solution matrix X.</param_description>
    </param_output_item>


  </param_output>



  <description>
  	<p> To solve for X either the continuous-time algebraic Riccatiequation or the discrete-time algebraic Riccati equation</p>
  </description>

  <used_function>SG02AD</used_function>
  <bibliography>http://slicot.org/objects/software/shared/doc/SG02AD.html</bibliography>

<examples>
  <example_item>
    <example_item_type>nelson</example_item_type>
    <example_item_description></example_item_description>
    <example_item_data><![CDATA[N = 2;
M = 1;
P = 3;
TOL = 0.0;
DICO = 'C';
JOBB = 'B';
FACT = 'B';
UPLO = 'U';
JOBL = 'Z';
SCAL = 'N';
SORT = 'S';
ACC = 'N';
A = [0.0  1.0;
   0.0  0.0];
E = [1.0  0.0;
   0.0  1.0];
B = [0.0;
   1.0];
Q = [1.0  0.0;
   0.0  1.0;
   0.0  0.0];
R = [0.0;
   0.0;
   1.0];
L = zeros(N, N);
[RCONDU, X, ALFAR, ALFAI, BETA, S, T, U, IWARN, INFO] = slicot_sg02ad(DICO, JOBB, FACT, UPLO, JOBL, SCAL, SORT, ACC, P, A, E, B, Q, R, L, TOL)]]>
    </example_item_data>
  </example_item>

</examples>

  <history>
    <history_item>
      <history_version>1.0.0</history_version>
      <history_description>initial version</history_description>
    </history_item>
  </history>

  <authors>
    <author_item>SLICOT Documentation</author_item>
  </authors>
</xmldoc>


